# **Martins Adesina**

Lagos, Lagos • 08139751464 • opehardesina@gmail.com

• linkedin.com/in/opeoluwa-adesina-725b8a10b/ • https://adesina-opeoluwa.netlify.app/

4+ years of experience developing robust web applications with React js, Typescript, YII, and AWS resources such as Cognito, SQS, SNS, and Amplify. Increased user engagement by 30%, website loading speed by 20%, and reduced load time by loading only necessary resources for initial loading. Delivered projects on-time with Agile methodologies, and added observability with Datadog for proactive actions.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Moove • 10/2021 - Present

## **Software Developer Frontend**

- I worked on integrating Frontend applications with AWS resources like Cognito.
- Worked on highly scalable Web Apps built with React js and Typescript
- Converted UI mock ups to React code following guidelines from the Design Team.
- · Worked closely with Backend Team while consuming REST API endpoints.
- I contributed to technical and user documentations following organisations best practices
- I wrote testable components for unit test and e2e test for process test using React Testing Library and Cypress
- I worked with Terraform to make changes on AWS platform with support of the DevOps team.
- Learned new technologies and adopted new tools quickly to maximize performance and contributions.
- Worked with AWS resources such as SQS, SNS, Amplify to deliver solutions.
- Increased user engagement by 30% in 3 months with optimized front-end code.
- Optimised load time of customer-facing applications by loading only resources needed for initial load, and then loading the rest of the resources on request.
- Added observability for Core web Vitals and third-party dependencies using Datadog as a monitoring tool. This improved visibility of application performance in production and allowed for proactive actions to be taken.

Go2 Solve • 07/2020 - 09/2021

### **Software Developer Frontend**

- Supported, maintained, documented, and enhanced software functionality.
- Completed assigned projects and tasks using standardized processes within timeline and requirements outlined by web portal team leads using React js.
- Refined and finalized designs by closely collaborating with senior engineers on code implementation, validation, and debugging.
- Achieved development milestones on-time by thriving under Agile-based frameworks.
- Learned new technologies and adopted new tools quickly to maximize performance and contributions.

- Accomplished project milestones and deliverables on-time with effective use of Agile methodologies.
- Developed a frontend feature that improved website loading speed by 20% in 3 months.

Bincom lct • Lagos, Lagos State, Nigeria • 01/2019 - 06/2020

#### **Backend Developer**

- Met application goals with frameworks like YII.
- Managed versions with Git, including tracking changes and seamlessly merging code from different features and updates.
- Enhanced Web sites and applications by developing robust databases.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Biochemistry B. Tech**

Federal University Of Technology. Akure

## **Senior Secondary School Certificate**

Latmos Comprehensive College

#### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

Attention to Detail, Collaboration, Scalability, Test Driven Development, Functional Programming, Following Instruction, Agile Software Development, Source Code Management, Design Principle, Emerging Technologies, Cash Collection, Payment Gateway, Best Practice, User Interface, Amazon Web Services, React Native, JavaScript, TypeScript, Terraform, Unit Testing, Representational State Transfer, ReactJS, Node.JS, DevOps Operations, Continuous integration, Hypertext Markup Language, OAuth, Cascading Style Sheet, Syntactically Awesome Style Sheets, Git, Amazon Simple Notification Service, Yii Framework, Reading, Travelling and meeting people, Coding